Guide to the James Jones Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1939-69; Series I; 14.5; (33 boxes)
  - SCREENPLAYS BY OTHERS
    - Go to the Widow-Maker by Thomas Wiseman
      - Typescript, ca. 1964 (Box 28, Folder 345)
      - Screenplay, typescript, unidentified draft, 1964 Dec 14 (Box 28, Folder 346)
      - Screenplay, typescript, 1st draft, 1969 Mar 27 (Box 28, Folder 347)
      - Screenplay, typescript, 2nd draft, 1969 Jun (Box 28, Folder 348)
      - Screenplay, typescript, unidentified draft, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 349)
      - Notes, 1969, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 350-51)
    - The Longest Day by Cornelius Ryan
      - Revised screenplay, typescript, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 352-53)
      - Notes, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 354-56)
    - The Sicilians ( Le Clan de Siciliens ) by Auguste Le Breton
      - Translation of original French script, 1969 Jan 8 (Box 29, Folder 357-58)
      - Notes, 1969, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 359-61)
    - Un Mur de Jerusalem by Frederick Rossit
      - Original draft, 1968 Dec 22 (Box 30, Folder 363)
      - Revised draft, 1968 Dec (Box 30, Folder 364)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Essays
      - Untitled essays, typescript, 1942, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 365-66)
      - "The Almost Revolution," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 367)
      - "The Hills Beyond," book review, typescript, 1942 Jul 20 (Box 31, Folder 368-70)
      - "The Making of a Man," holograph and typescript (Box 31, Folder 371)
      - "My Life a Month Ago and My Life Today," typescript, 1942 Jun 19 (Box 31, Folder 372-73)
      - "Language and Logic in Philosophy and Art," typescript, 1945 Mar 19 (Box 31, Folder 374)
      - "So What?," typescript, 1942 Jun 29 (Box 31, Folder 375-76)
      - "What I Expected to Learn in English 100B," typescript, ca. 1942 (Box 31, Folder 377)
    - Plays
      - All God's Chillun Ain't, typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 378)
    - Short Stories
      - Fragments, typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 379-87)
      - Untitled short stories, typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 388-96)
      - "And All Thru the House," typescript (Box 31, Folder 397)
      - "And the Grass Grows All Around," typescript (Box 31, Folder 398)
      - "Back Wash," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 399-400)
      - "Black Laughter," typescript, ca. 1942 (Box 31, Folder 401)
      - "The Boy Who Went Away," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 402)
      - "Business as Usual," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 403-04)
      - "A Couple of Grenades," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 405)
      - "Damon and Pythias," typescript (Box 31, Folder 406)
      - "Death (a study in agony)," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 407-09)
      - "December Seventh, 1941," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 410)
      - "Ducks in a Gallery," holograph, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 411)
      - "Father, Dear Father, Come Home With Me Now," typescript, ca. 1945 (Box 31, Folder 412-13)
      - "A Few Gallons of Gas," holograph, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 414)
      - "For They Shall Inherit the Earth," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 415)
      - "For They Shall Inherit the Laughter," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 416)
      - "Gold Star Soldier," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 417)
      - "The Golfer Story"
        - Holograph, 1969 Aug 8 (Box 31, Folder 418)
        - Typescript, 1969 Sep 4-5 (Box 31, Folder 419)
        - Notes, ca. 1969 (Box 31, Folder 420)
      - "Greater Love," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 421)
      - "Hidden Joke," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 422)
      - "Homecoming," typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 423-24)
      - "The Ice Cream Headache"
        - Typescript [6 drafts], 1966-67 (Box 32, Folder 425-30)
        - Notes, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 431)
      - "I Met a Guy," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 432-33)
      - "James Jones Lived Here," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 434-36)
      - "Joseph G. Doakes, Philosopher and Patriot," typescript (Box 33, Folder 437)
      - "Just Like the Girl," typescript, ca. 1946-47 (Box 33, Folder 438)
      - "The Knife," in Stag magazine, p. 28, 56-58, 1957, Dec., 1948 (Box 33, Folder 438a)
      - "The Man Who Entered an Empty Room," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 439)
      - "A Man Won't Understand," typescript (Box 33, Folder 440)
      - "None Can Sing So Wildly," typescript, ca. 1952 (Box 33, Folder 441-42)
      - "One Snowball via Clipper," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 443-44)
      - "Premonition," typescript, 1942 Jul 16 (Box 33, Folder 445-46)
      - "Ramon and Pythias," typescript (Box 33, Folder 447)
      - "Secondhand Man," typescript, ca. 1946-47 (Box 33, Folder 448-51)
      - "Selfishness," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 452-53)
      - "The Story of Peter Pringle," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 454)
      - "Story Without a Name," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 455-56)
      - "Superman and the Army," typescript (Box 33, Folder 457)
      - "A Talent of Lead," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 458-59)
      - "The Temper of Steel," typescript, ca. 1946-47 (Box 33, Folder 460)
      - "Thru the Bus' Front Window," typescript (Box 33, Folder 461)
      - "To be or not to be--a Dogrobber," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 462)
      - "The Weather Today," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 463)
      - "The Way It Is," advance proof, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 464)
      - "The Way to Die," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 465)
      - "What's Ten Gallons?", n.d. (Box 33, Folder 466)
      - "Who Wakes to Bridges Burned," typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 467-68)
      - "The Wind Blows, But It Carries a Stench," typescript (Box 33, Folder 469)
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 470)
    - Short Stories by Others
      - "Or you don't see Mama at all," by Lowney Handy, typescript (Box 33, Folder 471)
    - Speeches
      - [For Sargent Shriver?] Drafts 1-4, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 472)
- Correspondence, 1926-77; Series II; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  Series II, Correspondence, consists of six boxes of alphabetically arranged correspondence. Individuals are given separate listings based on their importance in the collection, or provided the file contains six or more items. The correspondence of those who appear one to five times, is filed alphabetically with the first letter of the surname in "Letter" general files. Correspondence includes the names of forty-four individuals and companies including the names of four people who appear in the section correspondence of others. There is also a section of alphabetically arranged fan mail.
  - Unidentified correspondence, 1944-51, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 472a)
  - "A" general, 1946-57 (Box 34, Folder 473-74)
  - Aaron Fuchs Company, 1956-57 (Box 34, Folder 475)
  - Aley, Ruth and Maxwell, 1945-50 (Box 34, Folder 476)
  - The Atlantic Monthly, 1947-49 (Box 34, Folder 477-78)
  - "B" general, 1949-57 (Box 34, Folder 479)
  - "C" general, 1949-57 (Box 34, Folder 480-81)
  - Carson, Margaret, 1942-53 (Box 34, Folder 482-85)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1945-57 (Box 34, Folder 486-87)
  - Clift, Montgomery, 1952-53 (Box 34, Folder 488)
  - Colliers, 1948,51 (Box 34, Folder 489)
  - Columbia Pictures Corporation, 1951-53 (Box 34, Folder 490)
  - "D" general, 1951-57 (Box 34, Folder 491-92)
  - "E" general, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 493)
  - Esquire, 1941-62 (Box 34, Folder 494)
  - "F" general, 1948-57 (Box 34, Folder 495)
  - Foote, Shelby, 1952-53 (Box 34, Folder 496)
  - "G" general, 1951-57 (Box 35, Folder 497)
  - "H" general, 1948-57 (Box 35, Folder 498)
  - Haish, Mollie, 1926-57 (Box 35, Folder 499-502)
  - Handy, Harry, 1944-51 (Box 35, Folder 503-04)
    See also: Box 39, folder 584
  - Handy, Lowney, 1944-51, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 505-07)
    See also: Box 39, folders 581-83
  - Harper's Magazine, 1947-48, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 508)
  - "I" general, 1952-57 (Box 35, Folder 509)
  - Ives, Marian, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 510)
  - "J" general, 1942-57 (Box 35, Folder 511)
  - Jones, George W. [Jeff], 1939-51 (Box 35, Folder 512-19)
  - Jones, Saddie, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 520)
  - "K" general, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 521)
  - "L" general, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 522)
  - Ladies Home Journal, 1949,57 (Box 35, Folder 523)
  - Lindsey, Willard, 1949-51 (Box 35, Folder 524)
  - "M" general, 1946-57 (Box 36, Folder 525)
  - MCA Artists, Ltd. Agency, 1951-57, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 526-29)
  - Mailer, Norman, 1952 Mar 2 (Box 36, Folder 530)
  - Manges, Horace S., 1957 (Box 36, Folder 531)
  - Marquand, John P., 1951-53 (Box 36, Folder 532)
  - Mitchell, Burroughs, 1949-57 (Box 36, Folder 533-40)
  - Moore, Virginia, 1942-43 (Box 36, Folder 541)
  - Moorepack, Howard, 1949-50 (Box 36, Folder 542)
  - "N" general, 1945-57,n.d. (Box 36, Folder 543)
  - "O" general, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 544)
  - "R" general, 1951-57 (Box 37, Folder 545)
  - Pearsley, Warren, 1949-50 (Box 37, Folder 546-47)
  - Perkins, Maxwell, 1946-47, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 548)
  - "R" general, 1944-51 (Box 37, Folder 549-51)
  - Rabinowitz, Harold, 1944-51 (Box 37, Folder 552)
  - Rafferty, Keen, 1949-51 (Box 37, Folder 553)
  - Russell and Volkening, Inc., 1949-50 (Box 37, Folder 554)
  - "S" general, 1946-57 (Box 37, Folder 555-56)
  - Sackrider, Don, 1949-50 (Box 37, Folder 557)
  - Schwartz, Laura V., 1943-51 (Box 37, Folder 558)
  - "Serge", 1948-49 (Box 37, Folder 559)
  - States, Billie, 1943 (Box 37, Folder 560)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1945-46 (Box 37, Folder 561)
  - Stroven, Carl, 1946-57 (Box 37, Folder 562)
  - Styron, William, 1952 (Box 37, Folder 563)
  - "T" general, 1957, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 564)
  - "U" general, 1945-57 (Box 37, Folder 565)
  - "V" general, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 566)
  - Van Dusen, Barbara, 1940-43 (Box 37, Folder 567-68)
  - "W" general, 1943-57, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 569)
  - Wheelock, John Hall, 1948-51 (Box 37, Folder 570-71)
  - Wiseman, Thomas, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 572)
  - "Y" general, ca. 1977 (Box 37, Folder 573)
  - "Z" general, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 574)
  - Zanuck, Darryl, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 575)
  - Fan Mail, 1951-57, n.d.
    - "A-Z" general, 1951-57 (Box 38, Folder 576-78)
    - unidentified, 1952, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 579)
  - Correspondence of Others
    - Various, 1945-57 (Box 39, Folder 580)
    - Handy, Lowney, 1944-57, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 581-83)
    - Handy, Harry, 1945-49, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 584)
    - Jones, George W. [Jeff], 1943-57 (Box 39, Folder 585)
    - Jones, Gloria, 1957, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 586)
- Family papers, 1939-58; Series III; 0.5; (1 box)
  Series III, Family Papers, consists primarily of personal papers, including financial papers, memorabilia, and photographs. The material is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Aqualung data with: You Can Be Drown Proof by Edward J. Linehan., n.d. (Box 40, Folder 587)
  - Financial records
    - From Here to Eternity, contract for the English edition, typescript, 1950 Dec 19 (Box 40, Folder 588)
    - Miscellaneous bills and receipts, 1944-57, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 589)
  - Illinois Skeet Shooting Association calendar of registered shoots, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 590)
  - Memorabilia
    - Chess games, recorded matches, 1957-58 (Box 40, Folder 591)
    - Cigarette holder, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 592)
    - Handy Colony letterhead paper (Box 40, Folder 593)
    - Map of Honolulu, Oahu and the Hawaiian Islands, 1945 Jun (Box 40, Folder 594)
    - Menu from the Hawaiian Room, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 595)
    - Patches: Aqua-Divers School, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 596)
    - Patient property card, pass, ca. 1944 (Box 40, Folder 597)
    - Miscellaneous postcards, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 598)
    - Ticket stubs, 1957 Sep 9 (Box 40, Folder 599)
    - Voice record made at the Empire State Observatory, 1939 Dec 15 (Box 40, Folder 600)
    - Warther, Ernest, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 601)
  - Midwestern Writers Conference, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 602)
  - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy
    See: Oversize, Box 42, folder 665
  - Newspaper clippings, 1917-65, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 603-05)
  - New York: miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 606)
  - P. E. N. Newsletter, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 607)
    - Asheville, North Carolina, 1947 Jun 22 (Box 40, Folder 608)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1947 Jun 18 (Box 40, Folder 609)
  - Photographs
    - Carson, Margaret, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 610)
    - Jones, Ada, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 611)
    - Jones, Gloria [5 photographs, 2 negatives], n.d. (Box 40, Folder 612)
      See also: Oversize, Box 42, folder 666
    - Jones, Gloria and James at the Beverly Hills Country Club, Newport, Kentucky (Box 40, Folder 613)
    - Jones, Gloria and James, Chicago Tribune photograph [5 photographs] (Box 40, Folder 614)
    - Jones, James and Gloria on a boating trip [11 photographs] (Box 40, Folder 615)
    - Jones, Gloria and James [14 slides] (Box 40, Folder 616)
    - Jones, James [5 photographs], n.d. (Box 40, Folder 617)
    - Jones, James, with unidentified man [2 photographs], n.d. (Box 40, Folder 618)
    - Jones, Ramon, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 619)
    - Unidentified people [9 photographs, 3 negatives], n.d. (Box 40, Folder 620)
  - Seven Stairs, a newsletter, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 621)
  - Sketches by an unidentified artist, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 622)
  - Television scripts
    - "The Faces of War", 1957 Nov 10 (Box 40, Folder 623)
    - "Person to Person", 1958 Jan 10 (Box 40, Folder 624)
  - Travel itineraries, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 625)
- Printed Material, 1951-58; Series IV; 1; (1 box)
  Series IV, Printed Material, consists of alphabetically arranged magazines and miscellaneous pamphlets collected by James Jones.
  - Magazines
    - Adult Psychology, The Magazine of Psychology for Everyone, 1955 Mar-Apr (Box 41, Folder 626)
    - The American Weekly, 1955 Apr 3 (Box 41, Folder 627)
    - The Chicago Tribune Magazine, 1955 May 22 (Box 41, Folder 628)
    - The Complete Life of Lena Horne, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 629)
    - Harper's Magazine, 1957 Sep (Box 41, Folder 630)
    - Inside Hollywood, 1956 (Box 41, Folder 631)
    - Inside Story, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 632)
    - Life, 1951-57 (Box 41, Folder 633-34)
    - The Marlon Brando Story--a Candid Profile, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 635)
    - Modern Screen, 1956 Nov (Box 41, Folder 636)
    - Movie Play, 1955 Jul (Box 41, Folder 637)
    - Movie Prevue, 1955 Jun (Box 41, Folder 638)
    - The New York Times Book Review, 1948 Jan 4 (Box 41, Folder 639)
    - People Today, 1955 Aug 24 (Box 41, Folder 640)
    - Picture Week, 1955 Sep 10 (Box 41, Folder 641)
    - Photoplay Annual, 1955-56 (Box 41, Folder 642-43)
    - Private Lives and Private Affairs, 1955 Mar (Box 41, Folder 644)
    - Publisher's Weekly, 1957 May 20 (Box 41, Folder 645)
    - Real, the Exciting Magazine, 1957-58 (Box 41, Folder 646-48)
    - The Royal Ballet, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 649)
    - Suppressed, 1955 May (Box 41, Folder 650)
    - T. V. and Movie Screen, 1955 Mar (Box 41, Folder 651)
    - T. V. Guide, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 652)
    - That Girl Ava, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 653)
    - That Guy Brando, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 654)
    - Time, 1954,59 (Box 41, Folder 655-56)
    - Top Secret, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 657-58)
    - Uncensored, 1955,57 (Box 41, Folder 659-61)
  - Pamphlets, 1956-58 (Box 41, Folder 662-63)
- Oversize
  - WRITINGS
    - The Re-Enlistment Blues, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 664)
  - FAMILY PAPERS
    - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, 1957 (Box 42, Folder 665)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Jones, Gloria Jones, James, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 666)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.25; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted Fragile. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 35, folders 500, 502, 504, 506-07, 518-19, 524 (Box 43, Folder 667-68)
  - Box 36, folders 525, 527 Box 37, folders 558, 564 (Box 43, Folder 669)
  - Box 38, folder 576 Box 39, folder 584 Box 40, folders 589, 603-05 (Box 43, Folder 670-73)
  - Box 41, folder 639 (Box 43, Folder 674)